Guide to the George Breitman Papers TAM.169
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series III: Political Organizations and Activities
  - Subseries III:B: Other Organizations (alphabetical listing)
    - Fourth International, 1936 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Fourth International, 1937 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Fourth International, 1938 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Fourth International, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Fourth International, 1940 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Fourth International, 1946 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Fourth International (Pablo/Pabloism), 1953 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Fourth International, 1954-1955 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Fourth International - World Congress minutes, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Fourth International, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Fourth International, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Fourth International, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Fourth International, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Fourth International, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Fourth International, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - FIT (Fourth Internationalist Tendency): Correspondence/Documents: Jan-Feb 1984, Jan 1984-Feb 1984 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Mar-1984 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Apr-1984 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: May-1984 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Jun-1984 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Jul-1984 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Aug-1984 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Sep-1984 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Oct-1984 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Nov-1984 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Dec-1984 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - FIT (Fourth Internationalist Tendency): Handbook for Marxist Studies, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - FIT: Minutes, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - FIT: Minutes - Cleveland Organizing Committee, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - FIT: Minutes - Los Angeles, 1984-1985 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - FIT: Minutes - Philadelphia Organizing Committee, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Jan-Feb 1985, Jan 1985-Feb 1985 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Mar-Apr 1985, Mar 1985-Apr 1985 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: May-Jun 1985, May 1985-Jun 1985 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Jul-Aug 1985, Jul 1985-Aug 1985 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Sep-Oct 1985, Sep 1985-Oct 1985 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - FIT: Correspondence/Documents: Nov-Dec 1985, Nov 1985-Dec 1985 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - F.I.T.: Correspondence/Documents - BIDOM #16, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - F.I.T.: Correspondence/Documents - BIDOM #17, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - F.I.T.: Correspondence/Documents - BIDOM #18, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - F.I.T.: Correspondence/Documents - Weissman, George - Memorial, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - F.I.T.: Minutes, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - F.I.T.: Correspondence/Documents, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - F.I.T.: Correspondence/Documents, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - League for a Revolutionary Workers Party, 1935 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Socialist Action: Jan-Oct 1983, Jan 1983-Oct 1983 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Socialist Action: Nov-83, Nov 1983 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Socialist Action: Dec-83, Dec 1983 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Socialist Action: Jan-84, Jan 1984 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Socialist Action: Feb-May 1984, Feb 1984-May 1984 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Socialist Action: Jun-84, Jun 1984 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Socialist Action, 1985-1986 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Socialist Action, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Socialist Party - Hansen, Joe - letters to Max Shachtman, 1938 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Socialist Party - internal documents, 1936-1937 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Socialist Party - Muste, A.J. "War is the central problem today..." [14 pp., untitled t.s.], 1936 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Socialist Party - National Action Committee minutes, 1937 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Socialist Party - National Action Committee minutes (1937), Breitman notes thereon, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Socialist Party - Newark, NJ, 1936-1937 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Spartacus Youth League, 1934-1936 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Workers Alliance, 1930s (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Workers Party US, 1934 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Workers Party US, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Workers Party US National Committee: Oct-1935 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Workers Party US, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Workers Party US National Committee: Oct-1936 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Workers Party US "What next in the Scottsboro case?" ("They shall not die" is not enough), 1936 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Workers Party US, undated (Box 42, Folder 15)
- Series IV. Writings
  - Subseries IV:A: Writings, general
    - Breitman: Lists of GB Writings, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Breitman: Bill of Rights [talk], undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Breitman: Castroism - revolutionary or centrist?; other Cuba writings: c.1978, ca.1978 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Breitman: Fiction, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Breitman: Lenin reading notes [38 pp], undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Breitman: Lesser evil politics, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Breitman: Prospects for socialism in the U.S. [talk], undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Breitman: Soviet Union and Stalinism [talk, notes]: c.1953, ca.1953 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Breitman: State capitalism, Bonapartism [lecture notes], undated (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Breitman: Workers and farmers government/question, undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Breitman: World War II era, undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Subseries IV:B: Party History
    - Party History: Correspondence re compilation of lists of names, chronologies, etc, 1980-1981 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Party History: "The Expelled", undated (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Party History: The Founding of the SWP - correspondence & notes, 1980-1981 (Box 43A, Folder 1)
    - Party History: The Founding of the SWP - glossary, undated (Box 43A, Folder 2)
    - Party History: The Founding of the SWP - part 6 (2nd convention), undated (Box 43A, Folder 3)
    - Party History: The Founding of the SWP - preface, undated (Box 43A, Folder 4)
    - Party History: The Founding of the SWP - indexes, lists, other reference tools, undated (Box 43A, Folder 5)
    - Party History: "Report to the PC on the character of the present period" (Breitman): c.1970s, ca.1970s (Box 43A, Folder 6)
  - Subseries IV:C: Malcolm X
    - Articles in The Militant on Malcolm X - list of, 1964-1965 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Assassination (of Malcolm X) articles, clippings, correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Audiotapes (lists etc.), 1960s (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Autobiography of Malcolm X: uncorrected proof ts, Breitman notes, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Breitman - articles and notes about Malcolm X, undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Breitman - correspondence - Cleaver, Eldridge: Nov 1966-Nov 1967 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Breitman - correspondence general, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Breitman correspondence: general: Jan-Jun 1966, Jan 1966-Jun 1966 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Breitman correspondence: general: Jul-Aug 1966, Jul 1966-Aug 1966 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Breitman correspondence: general: Sep-Dec 1966, Sep 1966-Dec 1966 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Breitman correspondence: general, 1967 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Breitman correspondence: general, 1968-1982 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Breitman: "The impact of Malcolm X": 2-Nov-66, Nov 1966 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Breitman: "Last year of Malcolm X" - typescript, 158 pp; reviews etc., 1966-1967 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Breitman: untitled manuscript re Malcolm X: c. 1966, ca.1966 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Ephemera: flyers, posters, etc., 1960s (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Lee, Paul - correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Lomax, Louis E., undated (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Malcolm X - articles, interviews, speeches, talks (transcriptions) (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Malcolm X - articles, interviews, speeches, talks - excerpts (transcriptions), undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Malcolm X -"Zionist logic" (article in "The Egytian Gazette"), Sep 17, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Malcolm X - [at] Harvard Law School Forum (ts, 47 pp. Edited by Breitman): 16-Dec-64, Dec 16 1964 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Malcolm X speaks (Breitman, ed.) Edited proof ts, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Militant: list of articles on Malcolm X, appearing 3/64 - 12/65, undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Novack, George - "Malcolm X" speech, at Militant Labor Forum, San Francisco: 4-May-76, May 1976 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Organization of Afro-American Unity, 1964-1965 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Malcolm X - Audobon ballroom, NYC (talk) 32 pp: 20-Dec-64, Dec 1964 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Malcolm X - Harlem Domestic Peace CORPS (talk) 37 pp. :12-Dec-65, Dec 12, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Malcolm X - "Message to the grass roots" (speech) at Northern Negro Grassroots Leadership Conference: 10-Nov-1963, Nov 10, 1963 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Malcolm X - The Pierre Berton show, Jan 1965 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Malcolm X - "Racism is the cancer that is destroying America" (article): 25-Aug-64, Aug 1964 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Malcolm X - SNCC Harlem (talk) 50 pp.: 1-Jan-65, Jan 1, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Subseries IV:D: African-Americans
    - Black organizations - documents, 1960s (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Breitman correspondence, undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Breitman "In defense of Black Power": Oct-66, Oct 1966 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Breitman "Race prejudice: when it began, when it will end", 1971 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Breitman "Shifts in the Negro Question", undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Breitman - Theory of the Negro struggle (4 classes), 1964 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Breitman writings, undated (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - By any means necessary (proposed magazine), 1967 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - The Communist movement and the Negroes 38 pp. galley proof, undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Freedom Now Party: Breitman correspondence, 1964 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Freedom Now Party: Breitman writings: c. 1964-c. 1965, ca.1964 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Freedom Now Party: Cruse, Harold - letter, 1963 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Guerin, Daniel/Negroes on the march 1956: Breitman correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Freedom Now Party documents, 1963-1966 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Freedom Now Party: Interview with Reverend Cleage (32 pp.): C. 1965, ca.1965 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Johnson, J. R (aka C.L.R. James) Preliminary notes on the Negro Question, 1939 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Northern Negro Grassroots Leadership Conference - Detroit, MI: Nov 8-10, 1963, Nov-63 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Novack, George - The meaning of the ghetto revolts [22 pp], 1967 (Box 48, Folder 2.5)
    - Parker, Albert (aka George Breitman) correspondence, 1941 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Parker, Albert (aka George Breitman) list of articles, 1939-1945, undated (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Parker, Albert (aka George Breitman) Militant articles, 1940-1943 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - SWP Internal Bulletin - Negro Question (list of articles, 1942-1958), undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Untitled typescript (partial) - for book on SWP & Negro Question?, undated (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Subseries IV:E: Cannon, James P.
    - Breitman: correspondence re Cannon, 1974-1985 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Breitman correspondence - Glotzer, Al, 1977-1981 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Breitman correspondence - Prometheus research library, 1984-1985 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Breitman (& others): lists, indexes of Cannon materials, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Cannon correspondence 1924-1060 - chronological list, 59 pp., undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Cannon correspondence - Dunne, Vincent [ltrs to], 1932, c1940 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Cannon correspondence - Houghton Library, Harvard, 1933-1940 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Cannon correspondence - Swabeck, Arne (Prinkipo, Turkey), 1933 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1922-1927 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents - CPUSA Political Committee Minutes: Oct. 27, 1928, Oct 1928 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1929-1935 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1936-1938 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1939-1949 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1951-1955 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1956-1957 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, 1959-1967 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Cannon correspondence/documents, undated (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Cannon "The Debs centennial" ts, 1956 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Cannon interviews (Dixon/Omari; Emiliano/Miguel), undated (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Cannon interview (by Harry Ring), 1973-1974 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Cannon interview (Sidney Lens), 1974 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Cannon personal papers & library - post mortem inventory, 1974-1975 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Cannon "The pre-communist revolutionary movement in the US" (2 lectures): Sep-54, Sep 1954 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Cannon - Trotsky correspondence [copies from other sources], 1936-1940 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Cannon: Writings (mainly newspaper articles), 1919-1934 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Glotzer, Al. "Reminiscences of J.P.C." (ts), 1975 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Morgan, Jeanne "The Cannon journal" (ts), undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Wald, Alan "Cannonites and Shachtmanites" (ts), 1984 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Wohlforth, Tim "James P. Cannon: in defense of a great revolutionary" (ts), undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Subseries IV:F: Trotsky, Leon
    - Breitman correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1987 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Breitman correspondence, undated (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Catalog of Trotsky's published works - prepared for Pioneer Publishers, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Derry, Felix Louis - Les Trotskyistes, Trotsky et al Question D'Alsace Lorraine, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 6.5)
    - Discussion with Lund [LT] transcript, 28 pp. [LT, Cannon, Dobbs, Hansen, etc.]: Jun 12-15, 1940, Jun 1940 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Evans, Les "An open break with Trotsky's permanent revolution" ts (120 pp.): c. 1982, ca.1982 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Novack, George "How a bureaucracy thinks" [review of LT ms "The philosophical tendencies of bureaucratization"], undated (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Glotzer, Al correspondence, 1929-1977 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Hansen, Joseph/Trotsky, Leon correspondence, 1937-1980 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Institute Leon Trotsky (Paris), 1977-1981 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Life of Leon Trotsky [film] reviews, 1972-1974 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Lore, Ludwig We Try Again - ch. 1 "Parting of the ways" (ts), undated (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Reich, Wilhelm, 1931-1935 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Revolution - table of contents & index 1935-1939, undated (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Shachtman at 64 by Tom Kreuger, undated (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Shachtman, Max "Dear comrades..." [from Bujukada, Turkey] 6 pp.: 9-Jun-33, Jun 1933 (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Shachtman, Max/Trotsky, Leon correspondence, 1929-1932 (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - Swabeck, Arne Letters to Cannon, from Prinkipo: Mar-33, Mar 1933 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Swabeck, Arne/Trotsky, Leon: exchange of letters, in Prinkipo: Mar-33, Mar 1933 (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - Trotsky, Leon: Cannon, letters to [compiled by John Wright], 1937-1972 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Trotsky/Cannon correspondence, 1929-1940 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Trotsky/Sedov correspondence, list of letters, undated (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Trotsky, Leon - letters, memos to American comrades, 1930-1941 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Trotsky, Leon - writings copies/translations, undated (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Trotsky, Leon - writings [compiled by John Wright], 1926-1947 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Trotsky, Natalia Sedov, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Unser Wort - table of contents, 1-104, 1933-1941, undated (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - La Verite- indexes 1-255, 1929-1936, undated (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - La Verite- table of contents 1-255, 1929-1936, undated (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Writings of Leon Trotsky (1929-1940) - celebration of completion of publication, 1978 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Subseries IV:G: Skoglund, Carl
    - Alien hearing transcript, 1942 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Auto-biographical sketches, 1955 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1980 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1981 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Breitman correspondence, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Carl Skoglund research project, 1982 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Deportation hearing transcript: 24-May-54, May 1954 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Furst, Randy correspondence re Skoglund in Minnesota (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Ostberg, Kjell correspondence re Skoglund in Sweden, 1980-1982 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Research file (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Skoglund centenary, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Turning point for Labor video project, 1979-1982 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Weissman/Skoglund interview transcripts, undated (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - FBI correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - FBI files (1 of 4), undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - FBI files (2 of 4), undated (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - FBI files (3 of 4), undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - FBI files (4 of 4), undated (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Subseries IV:H: Wald, Alan
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence: Jan-Jun 1978, Jan 1978-Jun 1978 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence: Jul-Dec 1978, Jul 1978-Dec 1978 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1979 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1982 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1983 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Wald, Alan correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Wald, Alan: Glotzer, Al - interview notes, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Wald, Alan (re) Mangan, Sherry, 1976 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Wald, Alan Morrow, Felix, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Wald, Alan "Memories of the Dewey Commission: forty years later", 1977 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Wald, Alan "Sculptor on the left: Duncan Ferguson & the search for wholeness": c.1981, ca.1981 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Wald, Alan: Wolfe, Bernard - obituary, 1985 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Subseries IV:I: Sinclair, Louis
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1968 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1971 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1973 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1977 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1979 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1980 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1981 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1982 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Sinclair, Louis correspondence, 1986 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Subseries IV:J: General Correspondence
    - Archer, John correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Broue, Pierre correspondence, 1972 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Broue, Pierre correspondence: Dec 1975-1977, Dec 1975-Dec 1977 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Broue, Pierre correspondence, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Broue, Pierre correspondence, 1979 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Broue, Pierre correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Dreyfus, Michel correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Heijenoot, Jean van correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Kofsky, Frank correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - London, Nat correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Marazzi, Antonella & Roberto correspondence, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Orveillon, Jean-Claude correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Shriver, George correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Subseries IV:K: Writings by Others
    - Alexander, Robert: The SWP purge of the early 1980s and its aftermath, 1984 (Box 61A, Folder 1)
    - Broue, Pierre: "Party opposition to Stalin (1930-1937) and the first Moscow trial" [18 pp], undated (Box 61A, Folder 2)
    - Broue, Pierre: "Revolution et contre revolution culturelle en Union Sovietique" [33 pp], undated (Box 61A, Folder 3)
    - Camejo, Peter: "Against centrism - the evolution of the Socialist Workers Party, 1978-1983" (Box 61A, Folder 4)
    - [Camejo, Peter]: "Fatalism vs critical consciousness, and an addendum on Pedro Camejo's Against sectarianism," by "Y", 1984 (Box 61A, Folder 5)
    - Feeley, Dianne: "What Cannon learned in the early Communist Party": Nov-82, Nov 1982 (Box 61A, Folder 6)
    - Flynn, Sean: "The Socialist Workers Party in crisis;" other articles: c. 1985, ca.1985 (Box 61A, Folder 7)
    - Le Blanc, Paul: "Permanent revolution in Nicaragua": Sep-83, Sep 1983 (Box 61A, Folder 8)
    - Le Blanc, Paul: "Revolutionary Marxism against Stalinism: Trotsky on the USSR and world revolution", 1984 (Box 61A, Folder 9)
    - London, Nathaniel: "The National Question and the Left Opposition in France, 1928-30: the debate on Alsace and Indochina", 1977 (Box 61A, Folder 10)
    - London, Nathaniel: "Trotsky, Trotskyism and the National Question", 1978 (Box 61A, Folder 11)
    - Wright, John G. (aka Usick Vandler), 1974-1977 (Box 61A, Folder 12)
- Series V: Lists and Indexes
  - Barnes, Jack: list of writings in internal bulletins, books, pamphlets, The Militant, et al., 1967-1983, undated (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Contents lists compiled by Louis Sinclair: Young Spartacus, The Communist, The Flag, Permanente Revolution(German), undated (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - English language [Trostkyist] bulletins of the 1930s: a list & table of contents, compiled by Louis Sinclair, undated (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Index, 1934-1960 ( New International; Fourth International; International Socialist Review) (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Internal Bulletins, contents list: CLA, WP, 1931-1936, undated (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - International Bulletins, contents list (CLO), 1931-1933, undated (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Labor Action(San Francisco): Articles list, 1:1-16, Nov. 28, 1936-May 1, 1937, undated (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - The Militant- list of obits and death notices, 1929-1981, undated (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - The Militant- articles list, 1928-1930; index, 1931, undated (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - The Militant- index, 1932; articles lists 1933-1934, undated (Box 62, Folder 10)